<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aviso Ventures</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/</link><description>Recent content on Aviso Ventures</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; Aviso Ventures</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://avisoventures.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Nail Media Interviews as a Startup Founder</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/how-to-nail-media-interviews-as-a-startup-founder/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/how-to-nail-media-interviews-as-a-startup-founder/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Early PR coaching taught me to be cautious:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Don’t say this.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Be careful—they might trick you.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Stick to the script.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But playing it safe leads to boring interviews. And boring = forgettable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what actually works 👇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💡 A few truths first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one knows anything about your startup.
Even if you think you’ve made it—VCs are reaching out, people are talking—you’re still a nobody to the broader world. Assume that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writers are not out to get you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you’re a massive jerk (and that becomes the story), most journalists aren’t looking to do a hit piece. They usually want to write something positive—or at the very least, balanced. Trashing a founder can come off as petty, and writers don’t want to risk burning bridges with your network (investors, lawyers, team, founder friends, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Learning from Mistakes with an Issue Log for Business Operations</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/ray-dalio-bridgewater-issue-log/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/ray-dalio-bridgewater-issue-log/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="learning-from-mistakes-with-an-issue-log-for-business-operations"&gt;Learning from Mistakes with an Issue Log for Business Operations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ray Dalio mentions in his book &amp;ldquo;Principles,&amp;rdquo; the Issue Log that was used to learn from mistakes and radically improve the culture and processes at Bridgewater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Errors or mistakes go in the Issue Log, with description, severity and &amp;ldquo;who was responsible&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it goes in the log, all is OK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If mistake is found, and not in the log, there will be problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Management&amp;rdquo; needs to review the issue log in a timely, regular manner with some process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some clarifications:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Effective Company-wide KPIs</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/effective-company-wide-kpis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/effective-company-wide-kpis/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="five-attributes-of-good-company-wide-kpis"&gt;Five Attributes of Good Company-wide KPIs&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="they-can-be-powerful-motivators-or-demotivators-if-done-incorrectly"&gt;They can be powerful motivators or demotivators if done incorrectly.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to present company-wide all-employees KPIs, make sure they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Durable – KPIs should remain stable over time and not change frequently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transparent – Results should be shared early and often with the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applicable – KPIs must apply broadly to everyone, not just a select few.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achievable – They must be realistically attainable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incremental – Progress should be measurable continuously, not only at rare &amp;ldquo;big bang&amp;rdquo; milestones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="background"&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Company-wide KPIs sound like a great idea: announce them, and everyone works toward improving them!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fundraising: When you say you have no competitors</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/fundraising-and-having-no-competitors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/fundraising-and-having-no-competitors/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When investors hear things like this for seed stage b2b companies it tends to mean one of two things and they&amp;rsquo;re both generally bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1️⃣ (most common) There is no market for this product and customers do not have this in a near term (and likely long term) budget to spend on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implication: This will make GTM cycles hard if not impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2️⃣ They are going to create a new market category with their product.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Moving from Engineer to Manager</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/moving-from-eng-to-manager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/moving-from-eng-to-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So you are thinking about going into management? Here&amp;rsquo;s the problem. You don&amp;rsquo;t know what management even is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have visibility into what your boss even does. Your crappy 1-1s with your boss and various reporting is a small fraction of the job. The rest you don&amp;rsquo;t see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most startups have &amp;ldquo;quasi-management.&amp;rdquo; The management for initial build out is very different than what management is at a mature company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management, for skilled, creative people, is a really new field. Like less than 100 years old. It&amp;rsquo;s changing all the time as we, meaning humans, figure it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of people in management should not be in management. That&amp;rsquo;s all I&amp;rsquo;ll say on that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About once a week someone asks for career advice on something. When it comes to management, I tell them to read:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avoiding the Enterprise Site License Trap for Seed-Stage Companies</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/seed-stage-enterprise-site-license/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/seed-stage-enterprise-site-license/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;#Avoiding the Enterprise Site License Trap for Seed-Stage Companies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-land-and-expand-outperforms-big-bang-deals"&gt;Why &amp;ldquo;Land and Expand&amp;rdquo; Outperforms &amp;ldquo;Big Bang&amp;rdquo; Deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A seed-stage company gets interest from a champion at a Very Big Company. The champion loves the product so much that they propose an enterprise site license. Excitement surges—this could be a six-figure deal and a marquee reference customer! The sales rep, eager for a big win, goes all in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hold on. While every situation is unique, here’s why this often goes sideways:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Talk to 90 Potential Customers in 90 Days</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/90-customer-calls-in-90-days/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/90-customer-calls-in-90-days/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken with two founders who have tackled a &amp;ldquo;90 in 90 days challenge&amp;rdquo; to engage potential customers. For founders, especially tech founders, adjusting to &amp;ldquo;always-on sales&amp;rdquo; can be challenging, which is why I love this gamified approach to customer outreach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one case, the founder was pre-product and wasn’t actively selling anything yet. Instead, he used the opportunity to ask crucial product questions, identify potential buyers, determine budget sources, and understand their willingness to pay. During each call or in-person meeting, he also asked for introductions to two additional contacts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The First 15 Words in your SDR/BDR Email</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/bdr-sdr-first-15-words-in-email/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/bdr-sdr-first-15-words-in-email/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;🗣️✉️ BDR/SDRs: The First 15 Words Decide if I Open An Email
Make them Count, Here&amp;rsquo;s How.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of the BDR / SDR is critical for enterprise sales. However open rates have been dropping. That&amp;rsquo;s no surprise as the volume has been increasing. AI is not helping. AI has been trained on crappy emails to generate&amp;hellip; more crappy email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="heres-how-to-fix-your-outbound-emails"&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to fix your outbound emails.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first 10-15 words of the email are critical. Look at the screenshot. That&amp;rsquo;s how any busy person decides if they open the email. I&amp;rsquo;ll let you figure out how to state your value proposition or what problem you are solving in under 15 words. But to do it, follow these five rules:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>