<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aviso Ventures</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/</link><description>Recent content on Aviso Ventures</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; Aviso Ventures</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://avisoventures.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Controlling Dilution - The Series</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution/</guid><description>Founder (and employee) dilution during fundraising is natural and required. How much dilution however is, at least partially, controllable. And the amount of dilution can be the difference between an &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; exit and &amp;ldquo;f-you money&amp;rdquo; exit. It&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon for founders to own less than 5% of the company after exit, and in some cases 1%. At Signal Sciecnes, the founders still controled over 46% of the company at exit. How did we do it?</description></item><item><title>Controlling Dilution 1 - Taking Less Money</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-1-take-less-money/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-1-take-less-money/</guid><description>This is part of a series on reducing founder dilution.
This one is kind of a “duh” concept but before starting a company myself, I mostly figured that the more money you raised the better it was for the company. You read headlines about fundraises and see massive numbers and associate the higher the number the better the company is doing. Sorta… Yes, it means investors were willing to put more money into a company to back them, but it also means more of the company was sold in the process.</description></item><item><title>Controlling Dilution 2 - Raising at a Higher Valuation</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-2-higher-valuation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-2-higher-valuation/</guid><description>This is part of a series on controlling founder dilution during fundraising.
This one is also kind of a no-brainer that the higher the valuation you get from investors in each round of funding, the higher the price is per share thus cash invested in the company at lower rates of dilution.
One of the best ways I’ve seen this executed in early rounds of funding is to raise a SAFE instead of a priced round to push out when the value gets set for the purchase price of equity.</description></item><item><title>Controlling Dilution 3 - The Employee Option Pool</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-3-option-pool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-3-option-pool/</guid><description>This is part of a series on controlling founder dilution during fundraising.
This was probably the one I was the least prepared for when it came to dilution management and I have my seed funder Michael Dearing from Harrison Metal to thank for this lesson. When you start the company you will create a pool of equity that you set aside for employees instead of just granting shares each time a new employee starts (like I thought happened).</description></item><item><title>Controlling Dilution 4 - Raise Debt Instead of Equity</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-4-debt-instead-of-equity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-4-debt-instead-of-equity/</guid><description>This is part of series on controlling founder dilution during fundraising.
Debt basically means you’re raising money from a bank/financial entity that will loan you money that you will have to pay back in the future but that you can use to finance growth of your company instead of having to sell equity and dilute the company. This is an intuitive concept but a relatively uncommon path for raising money so I find it to be something a lot of founders I know don’t think about as much.</description></item><item><title>Controlling Dilution 5 - Ask Your Lawyer</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-5-leverage-your-lawyer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-5-leverage-your-lawyer/</guid><description>This is part of a series on controlling founder dilution during fundraising.
This is also one I find almost all new founders being a bit blindsided by and not prepared for and you’re probably thinking “how does a good lawyer help me reduce dilution???” Lawyers to non-founders typically = expensive and pedantic/rule oriented. While this can be true the best startup lawyers are worth their weight in gold and more. They live and breathe the terms of funding deals and are aware of current trends more than almost anyone who will be on the company’s side of a deal.</description></item><item><title>Controlling Dilution 6 - Sell the Company</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-6-sell-the-company/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-6-sell-the-company/</guid><description>This article is part of a series on controlling founder dilution.
When doing fundraising it&amp;rsquo;s natural to focus on increasing the company&amp;rsquo;s valuation. However, you are in fact making an independant bet that you can grow the company larger than your personal dilution. Otherwise why bother doing it? We have seen numerous cases of founders &amp;ldquo;doubling down&amp;rdquo; by taking VC funding, having dilution, workng 5 more years, and then get the exact same exit they would have gotten in the beginning.</description></item><item><title>Controlling Dilution 7 - Ask The Board for More</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-7-ask-for-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/controlling-dilution-7-ask-for-more/</guid><description>This is part of a series on controlling foudner dilution.
One antonymn of &amp;ldquo;dilute&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;enrich,&amp;rdquo; and you can definitely enrich yourself. As a founder you are an employee like everyone else. And the board wants you motivated. The board can issue new option grants to you, which has the opposite effect of dillution.
The board is unlikely to be proactive here, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to ask. Typically these shares don&amp;rsquo;t come out of the option pool, but from the investor&amp;rsquo;s own shares, so don&amp;rsquo;t expect a whole lot here.</description></item><item><title>Masters of Scale - Getting To No</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/masters-of-scale-01-getting-to-no/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/masters-of-scale-01-getting-to-no/</guid><description>My wife brought home Reid Hoffman’s “Masters of Scale” from the public library.: If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Reid, he&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; uh&amp;hellip; a very well known investor, focusing primarily on business with network effects. Oh yeah he founded LinkedIn too.
The first chapter is “Getting to No” – all about the different types of Nos you’ll get from investors, and how to use them to your advantage. Signal Sciences certainly had its share of Nos over the course of five fundraising rounds, so I was curious to hear what Reid Hoffman has to say.</description></item><item><title>The Legend of Magic Box</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/posts/the-legend-of-magic-box/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/posts/the-legend-of-magic-box/</guid><description>“Hey Nick… can we add a box on the marketing website to collect email addresses?”
My head exploded. We are three months into Signal Sciences. I’m the CTO, Founder, Lead Engineer, and probably a dozen more titles. I’m spending long days trying to get a round trip working on the product. And oh yeah, I’m working in Tokyo dealing with 3 timezones in North America. My head exploded. At the previous job I was working on e-mail infrastructure that sent millions of emails for a very large customer base.</description></item><item><title>About Aviso Ventures</title><link>https://avisoventures.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://avisoventures.com/about/</guid><description>Andrew and Nick What&amp;rsquo;s in a Name Nuts and Bolts It&amp;rsquo;s a static site, made with Hugo, and hosted on Github Pages and deployed using Github Actions.</description></item></channel></rss>